血仇
小萨拉・伊丽莎白多大了?
How old was little Sarah Elizabeth?
噢 快一岁了
Oh, she was just shy of a year.
内衬着蓝丝绒
Lined with blue velvet.
好的
Yeah.
是的 她会喜欢的
Yeah, she'd like that.
古德帕斯丘先生 做得不错
It'll do, Mr. Goodpasture.
我给你们一点时间吧
I'll give you some time.
- 她会在里面躺得很舒服的 - 是的
- She'll rest easy in that. - Yeah.
可怜的小女孩
Poor little girl.
你觉得等我也上了天堂
You think me and Sarah Elizabeth
我和萨拉・伊丽莎白还能认出彼此吗?
will recognize each other when I get to heaven?
噢 我想你的兄弟们会照顾好她的
Oh, I expect your brothers will take care of her.
你会认出他们的
You'll recognize them.
他们杀了人
They done murder.
他们或许去不了天堂
They might not get there.
我们得走了
We need to go.
是我 兰塞姆
It's ransom.
你找我?
You sent for me?
备好马
Saddle the horses.
我得到消息...
I got me a tip about...
哈特菲尔德家有三个虔诚的基督教徒
Three good Christian Hatfields
等着我们去抓
we gonna apprehend.
我们现在赶紧越过拖轮河...
We go now across the river quick...
给他们来个措手不及
They won't have time to hide.
我会尽快地围捕那些人
I'll round up the men posthaste.
你要来吗?
You coming?
他会去的
He will be.
来吧!
Come on!
? 你是否靠羔羊宝血洗净? ?
Are you washed in the blood of the Lamb?
? 你是否已经 ?
Are you fully trust?
? 完全信靠 ?
In his grace
? 主救恩 ?
This hour
? 是否靠耶稣血... ?
Are you washed...
兄弟
Brother.
那是汤姆・钱伯斯
That's Tom Chambers.
抓住他
Get him.
他就在那 还有他
There he is. Him too.
你不能这样做
You can't do this.
下一个是谁?
Who's the next one?
这是怎么回事?
What is this?
这里是圣殿!
This is the house of God!
女士
Ma'am.
走吧 伙计们
Let's get out of here, boys.
? 你是否靠宝血? ?
Are you washed in the blood?
? 靠羔羊宝血... ?
In the soul...
吁
Whoa.
发生什么事了?
What's all the ruckus?
人们在庆祝菲利普斯先生的成功
Folks are celebrating Mr. Phillips' success.
他还没有抓住恶魔昂斯呢
He hasn't caught Devil Anse yet.
他很虚弱
He's poorly.
得了胸膜炎
He got pleurisy.
吉姆
Jim.
看你这凄惨的样子
Ain't you a sorry sight.
要我迟一点再来吗?
Want I should come back later?
有话直说吧
Speak your mind.
教堂唱圣歌时
Phillips' gang
菲利普斯那帮子人突然闯了进来
raided services at the tug fork church,
抓走了汤姆・钱伯斯和马洪兄弟
seized Tom Chambers and the Mahon brothers,
还蛮横无理地打了加勒特牧师一拳
smacked preacher Garrett for no apparent reason.
昂斯 他们可是打了我们一巴掌
Anse, they are shoving it in our face.
是的
Yeah.
你的人约翰・B・弗洛伊德有什么消息吗?
Any word from your man John B. Floyd?
文迪州长简直垃圾不如
Governor Windy ain't doing shit,
整天只听信律师们的谗言
too busy letting lawyers get in his ear
毫不理会那些纽约的耙粪记者们
and getting his back up against these New York muckrakers
把我们称作为"野人山部落"
calling us a "Savage Mountain Tribe."
我们得依靠自己 向来如此
It's up to us, like always.
你有什么打算?
What do you propose?
擒贼先擒王
Cut off the head of the snake.
要想抓住弗兰克・菲利普斯是非常困难的
Be awful treacherous going after Frank Phillips.
他身边有一个军队跟着呢
He's got an army around him.
不 他是...他只是爪牙
No, he's... he's the fangs.
我们得杀了兰德尔・麦考伊
We ought to kill Randall McCoy.
先生 我是佩里・克莱因律师
I'm attorney Perry Cline, esquire.
我将代表你们 除非法庭认为有必要
I'll represent you till the court deems it necessary
委任一位公设辩护人
to appoint a public defender.
难道留着你做我们的律师
You think we got a better chance
我们会有更大的机会胜诉吗?
if we keep you on as our lawyer?
这要取决于你们
Well, it's up to you.
我比谁都要了解这案子的情况
I do know the circumstances of the case better than anyone.
这些邮资信封是用来联系你们家人的
Now, these stamped envelopes are to contact your family members
让他们知道你们没被亏待
to assure them you're being well-treated
还有准备好给我的聘请定金
and to arrange payment of my retainer.
将五十美元现金送到我的办公室
That's $50 cash receivable at my office.
你们杀了我的儿子们
You killed my sons.
你那些杀人犯儿子
Your murdering sons.
定罪之前任何人都是无罪的
Not guilty till proved innocent,
像你这样的人也理应得到公平审判
men like you who deserved a fair trial.
我祈祷你被绞死
I pray you hang.
我会提供造绞刑架的木材
I will supply the lumber for the gallows,
我还会帮你系紧绞绳的结
and I will tie the knot on your rope.
等你脖子断了 我会感到高兴
And when your neck snaps, I will rejoice
因为你将被不灭的地狱之火所焚烧!
as you are sent to boil in eternal damnation's hellfire!
也祝你圣诞快乐 先生
A Merry Christmas to you, too, sir.
你没事吧 妈妈?
You all right, ma?
你听见了吗?
You hear that?
听见什么?
Hear what?
嘘
Shh.
他们会从那边来
They'll come from over there.
谁?
Who will?
哈特菲尔德家的人 他们会从那边来
Hatfields, they'll come from over there.
哈特菲尔德家的人?
Hatfields?
妈 哈特菲尔德家的人正躲着恶人弗兰克呢
Ma, Hatfields are hiding out from bad Frank.
他们不会过来河这边的
They ain't gonna come across this side of the river.
进去吧 好吗?
Let's go inside, huh?
今晚没有人会来
No one's coming tonight.
我不是说今晚
It's not tonight I speak of.
我们就像猎物一样被那些该死的赏金猎人追捕
We're hunted like animals by hired trash.
家人和朋友 或被绑架 或被谋杀
Family and friends kidnapped and murdered.
法律袖手旁观
The law stood by.
法律无所作为
The law has done nothing.
尽管如此 如果有什么....
Even so, if there was anything...
我可以付出什么
anything I had that, by giving it,
来结束这场血腥争斗
I could end this bloody struggle,
我会心甘情愿地付出
I would give it gladly.
我愿意献出我的生命来终止这场战争
I'd give my life if it would end this.
你不会的
You would not.
我不愿意献出的是
What I will not give
我族人的哪怕一滴血
is one more drop of this family's blood.
所以今晚
So tonight,
在这新年前夕
this new year's Eve,
让我们了结这一切吧
we end this forever.
我愿意和你一起去 哈特菲尔德先生
Im's with you, Mr. Hatfield.
你不能跟着来 比利
You ain't coming, Billy.
你仍未准备好
You ain't ready.
感谢星星 我没来得太晚吧
Thank the stars I ain't too late.
有的是时间 约翰斯
Lots of time, Johnse.
我们正等着你爸爸咳完呢
We all just waiting for your pa to finish his coughing fit.
我们可以在黎明时分到达那里
We can be there by dawn,
让太阳照耀着我们的后背前行
make our approach with the sun at our backs.
早晨来临
The time of the morning,
那时他们一定毫无防备
the day it is, they won't expect nothing.
我们无需伤害其他人
We harm no one we don't have to.
一旦兰德尔看清局势
Once Randall sees how it is,
他会为了保护其他人而主动投降
he'll surrender himself to protect the others from harm.
我们生擒他
We take him alive.
我觉得我们该干掉他
Thought we was getting rid of him.
一旦兰德尔・麦考伊被捉获
Once Randall McCoy's extradited,
成为我们的战俘 我们...
as our prisoner of war, we...
我们在西弗吉尼亚州处决他
we execute him here in West Virginia,
他在哪犯下的罪行
the state where he committed his crimes.
就该在哪被处决
As is proper.
有点头晕
A mite dizzy.
不小心踩在了石头上了
Stepped on a stone or something.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know.
我们还是要送你去医生那里
We still got to get you to the doc.
不 没有时间了
No, there's no time.
爸爸 你太虚弱了
You're too sick, pa.
就这样办吧
Well, we can do this.
该死的
Damn.
昂斯
Anse.
要是你一直这样咳嗽而暴露了我们的行踪
Be a worthless trip if you start coughing like that
这趟就白去了
and give us all away.
只要毫发无损地带兰德尔一人回来即可
No one but Randall taken and him not harmed.
毫发无损的
Him not harmed,
否则你给我一个交代
or you answer to me.
好的 全部出发
All right, y'all.
上马
Saddle up.
你会好起来的 昂斯
You're gonna beat it, Anse.
我们会抓到兰德尔的
And we'll get Randall.
兰德尔 醒醒
Randall, wake up.
他们来了
They're here.
嘘
Shh.
怎么了 爸爸?
What is it, poppy?
快让孩子们下来
Get them children down.
快下来
Get down.
走
Go.
地狱即是我的天堂
May hell be my heaven,
谁要是违抗我的命令擅自开枪
I will kill any man who goes back on me
我就杀了他
if powder will burn.
好吧 按计划行事 各自就位
All right, as planned. Go on now.
就位
Go on.
爸爸说只抓兰德尔
You know, pa said just Randall.
我们得把他带回西弗吉尼亚州
We take him back over the tug to West Virginia
你觉得兰德尔・麦考伊
You think Randall McCoy's gonna let himself
会举手投降吗?
get took alive?
至少得试一试
We got to try.
兰德尔・麦考伊!
Randall McCoy!
你的死期到了
Your final day has dawned.
想要救你家人一命的话
Save your family.
就快点投降吧
Surrender yourself.
听到了吗?
You hear me?
你的死期到了
Your final day has dawned.
吉姆叔叔!
Uncle Jim!
吉姆
Jim.
这里已经被我们包围了
We got all sides covered now,
每一扇门 每一扇窗 每一个鼠穴
every door, window, and rathole.
他们休想从我们眼皮子底下溜走
Ain't nobody gonna get out without us seeing them.
谁负责后面?
Who's got the back?
淡毛科顿
Cotton Top.
Cotton Top表示有极淡色头发的人 以下译成"淡毛科顿"
约翰斯和他一起
Johnse's with him.
我去确认一下
I'll go check them out.
你的农场已经被我们包围了 麦考伊
We got your whole farm surrounded, McCoy.
你最好快点出来
Might as well come on out.
立刻投降 我们就会放过你的家人!
Do it now, and we spare your family!
我看到吉姆・万斯了
I seen that Jim Vance.
盖・哈特菲尔德还有其他人
Cap Hatfield and the others
应该都埋伏起来了
are out of sight taking cover.
多少人?
How many?
十五个 也许更多
15, probably more.
过来
Come on.
快过来
躲在后面 坐下来
Get behind and sit.
你也是
You too.
不要轻举妄动 除非他们先开枪
Don't shoot unless they do
或者有人冲过来
or someone charges.
不管怎么样 我都打不中他们的
I can't get a good shot no ways.
嘘
Shh.
抱歉
Sorry.
这个调子一直在我脑海里回响
I got this tune stuck in my head.
约翰斯去哪了?
Where's Johnse?
我只知道他要我守住后面
He said to watch the back is all I know.
不要让任何人出来
Don't let no one out.
守住这里
Watch the back.
兰德尔・麦考伊 出来投降面对现实吧
Randall McCoy, come on out and face the day,
否则的话 我就把你的房子烧掉
or else I have to burn your house down.
你希望你的孩子们被活活烧死吗?
You want your little ones consumed in fire?
我们很好 不要担心
We're all right. Don't worry.
你希望听到他们的小身躯
Their wee bodies a-hissing
被火炙烤发出嘶嘶声吗?
and a-steaming?
兰德尔!
Randall!
从后面逃出去 然后向树林方向跑
Go out the back, and run for the woods.
我必须出去
I got to go out there.
我现在出去和吉姆・万斯最后摊牌的话
If I can get a showdown with Jim Vance,
或许其他人就会退缩
maybe the others will back down.
兰德尔他会毫不留情地杀死你的
Randall, he'll shoot you down like you was nothing.
我求求你了 丈夫
I'm begging you, husband,
趁着现在赶紧从后门溜出去
slip out the back while you can.
如果知道你逃走了 他们就会放了我们的
If they know you're gone, they'll leave us be.
淡毛科顿 那是什么?
Cotton Top, what's that?
停止射击!
Hold your fire!
趴下! 趴下!
Get down! Get down!
停火!
Hold on!
该死的!
God damn it!
我还没有下命令!
I didn't order yet!
停火!
Hold on!
我再说一次 停止射击!
I said, hold your fire!
他妈的怎么回事?
What the hell?
科顿先开枪的
Cotton started shooting.
肯定是看到麦考伊探头探脑了
Must have seen McCoy stick his head out.
快去看看
Go find out.
嘿 爸爸不在这里!
Hey, my pa's not here!
他昨晚在派克维尔过夜的!
He stayed over in Pikeville last night!
我说让他出来!
I said for him to come out!
他不在这里!
He's not here!
除了我以外
Ain't nobody in here but me,
就只有些女人和孩子了
except women and childrens.
兰德尔!
Randall!
我们就在这里一直等到你出来为止
We're all waiting for you.
他不在这里!
He's not here!
天父啊 请救救我的家人
Heavenly father, spare my family,
消灭我的敌人
and smite my enemy.
我祈求你 看在我们无助的份上
I beg of you, have mercy in our hour of need.
祈求你的怜恤 主耶稣
Have mercy, lord Jesus.
他
He
科顿 我们说过
cotton, we said,
"不要让任何人从后面出来"
"Let nobody out the back."
不要让任何人从后面出来!
Nobody out the back!
抱歉
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
只能来硬的了
Discourtesy is what it is.
狗娘养的!
You son of a bitch!
我们必须把火扑灭 快拿水
We got to get the fires out. We need more water.
用牛奶
Use the buttermilk.
你个没种的 竟然连女人和孩子都不放过!
You're burning women and children, you coward!
你就是个魔鬼 吉姆・万斯
What kind of devil are you, Jim Vance?
爱丽菲尔!
Alifair!
听我说
Now, you listen to me.
带着妈妈和弟弟妹妹从后面溜出去  好吗?
You get ma and the kids out the back, all right?
妈妈 快点 我们快走
Mama, come on. Let's go.
快点 快点出去
Go on. Get them out.
照顾好弟弟妹妹们 爱丽菲尔
Mind the babies, Alifair.
我随后就来
I'll be along.
妈妈 快走 快 快!
Ma. Go, go, go!
别停
Don't stop.
快点
Go on.
快点 范妮
Go on, Fanny.
你们应该待在里面的
You got to go back inside.
- 快走 - 快回去!
- Keep going. - Get back inside!
不可以这样
It ain't allowed.
我让他们...我让他们从后面溜出去了
I let them... I let them out the back.
你打死一个
You got one.
干得不错
That's good enough.
他们不可以这样
They ain't allowed.
快把兰德尔・麦考伊交出来!
I want Randall McCoy!
我这就把他儿子交给你!
Well, you got his son!
爸爸
Poppy.
嘿
Hey.
范妮
Fanny.
妈妈呢?
Where's your mother?
爱丽菲尔受伤了
Alifair got hurt.
停止射击
Hold your fire.
你他妈在做什么?
What the hell are you doing?
愚蠢的疯婆子
Crazy stupid bitch.
血仇
我做了一个梦
I was having a dream,
梦中 莎莉 说 "他们来了"
and Sally said, "They're here."
我听到吉姆・万斯叫嚣着
I heard Jim Vance yelling,
"兰德尔・麦考伊 快出来受死吧!"
"Randall McCoy, come out and face the day!"
然后他们就对我穷追不舍
And it was me they was after.
你可以把头往后面仰一点吗?
Can you lean your head back?
我得检查一下你的眼睛
I need to look in your eye.
我告诉莎莉 "我必须出去"
I told Sally, "I got to go out there."
她说 "如果你出去的话 他们会杀死你的"
She said, "You do, they'll kill you.
"快从后面逃出去"
"Try and get out the back."
"如果你逃出去 我和孩子们就安全了"
"Me and the children, we'll be safe when you're gone."
安全了
Safe.
一切都会没事的
It's gonna be all right.
- 我要我的罗西 - 我知道 亲爱的
- I want my Rosie. - I know, sweetheart.
我匆匆向树林里面跑去
I lit out and made for the woods.
接着我听到枪声
Then I heard the shooting.
不一会 我就看到浓烟滚滚
After a while, I seen the smoke.
我看到了我的孩子们
Then I saw the children.
孩子们告诉我
The children told me
爱丽菲尔带着他们从火场逃出来的时候
Alifair was leading them away from the fire
被他们打中了
when they shot her.
我把他们带进树林深处
I took them deeper in the woods.
我们跪下向上帝祈祷
We knelt, and we prayed.
当我回去的时候 他们已经走了
When I got back, they was gone.
房子着火了
The house was on fire
我看见恶魔在烈火之中
I see the devil in the fire
他踱着步
He was walking aroud
嘲笑我
Laughed at me
菲利普斯先生
Mr. Phillips.
你得来看看这个
You got to see this.
莎莉就躺在卡尔文不远处
Sally was laying on the ground next to Calvin.
我把她扶起来 挽着她的胳膊
I picked her up, and I held her in my arms
不知道过了多长时间
for I don't know how long.
当我再次抬头的时候
And when I next looked up,
你就出现在我面前
you was here.
你儿子吉姆正在来接孩子的路上
Your son Jim is on his way to get the kids.
你和麦考伊小姐可以待在我那里
You and Miss McCoy will stay at my house.
我向仁慈的上帝祈祷 但他对我却毫无怜悯
I prayed to a merciful God who showed us no mercy.
兰德尔 我们要成就上帝的意愿
His will, Randall, not our, will be done.
这是他的意愿吗?
This is his will?
我的孩子死了 我的妻子受伤了
My children dead, my wife hurt,
我的房子毁了?
and my house burned?
上帝在哪?
Where was God?
如果这是他的意愿 那这算哪门子上帝?
If this is his will, what kind of God is that?
哪门子上帝?
What kind of God is that?
是麦考伊家的另一个女儿
It's the other McCoy girl.
看上去她已经死了
Looks like she's seen the devil.
不管我们现在想怎么做
Whatever we want now.
规则已经定好了
Rules are done.
你好 查尔斯
Hey, Charles.
怎么样了?
What?
看着一家人安安静静地吃饭
You know, looking at this family peacefully feeding
让我感慨 我们为什么要杀麦考伊家的人
reminds a body of why we kill McCoys.
坐下 坐下
Sit down. Sit down.
进行得并不顺利
It didn't turn out so well.
告诉我
Tell me.
那个该死的弱智科顿
That goddamn half-wit cotton turd.
这话可能在孩子们面前说不合适
Oh, this probably ain't fit for the ears of young 'uns.
去洗洗
Go wash.
带上你弟弟 快去
Take your brothers. Let's go.
走吧 顺便关上门
Go. Shut the door behind you.
快说吧
Just say it.
他的家人们妨碍了
Our foray against old Randall was interfered with
我们对老兰德尔的偷袭
by family members.
老兰德尔像只受惊的兔子似的逃跑了
While old Randall was running scared like a jackrabbit,
他的儿子卡尔文...
his heir Calvin...
抱着必死的决心
Come charging us,
冲出来迎战我们
shooting with deadly intent.
我除了杀他 别无选择
I had no choice but to kill him.
你说"家人"
You said "family."
嗯
Ah.
兰德尔的一个年岁稍大的女儿 嗯...
One of old Randall's older daughters, um...
她在逃跑的时候被误杀
She got in the way and got killed accidental.
被误杀的可能还不止她一个
There may have been others.
我们试图用火把他们逼出来
We tried to burn them out.
这些都是我们预料不到的 昂斯
And all unforeseen, Anse.
但是你了解你儿子盖 对吧?
But you know your boy, Cap?
他现在做的很好
He done good now.
所以兰德尔逃跑了
And Randall got away.
是的
Yup.
那兰德尔的妻子呢?
And what of Randall's wife?
她穿着睡衣跑出来
She run mad, barreled straight at me
发了疯似的拿枪指着我
in her dishabille.
然后呢?
And?
然后我...
And I...
我用我的枪托
I laid her in the back of the ear
把她砸晕在地
with my rifle butt.
现在应该已经死了
I believe she's done.
我们现在怎么办 吉姆?
What we do now, Jim?
把他们全杀了?
Kill them all?
血仇
牧师
Reverend.
怎么了?
What is it?
女士 我有一些噩耗要告诉你
Ma'am, I have some terrible news.
你不敢告诉我 你和你那些侩子手家人
Couldn't tell me what you and your butchering family
这回都干了什么 是吧?
did this time, could you?
你敢吗?
Could you?
妈的 住手!
God damn it, stop it!
令人发指!
Horrible!
真是令人发指!
Just horrible!
怎么会有人在上帝的眼皮底下
How could any man on God's green earth
做出如此恐怖的事?
do something so horrible?
不是我干的!
It wasn't me!
怎么可能?
How?
该死的
God damn it.
吉姆叔叔和他们
Uncle Jim and them
想彻底摆脱兰德尔・麦考伊
was trying to get rid of Randall McCoy
这样就可以结束这场战争
so all this fighting gets stopped.
他们的出发点是好的
Their intentions was right.
哦 他们的出发点是好的
Oh, their intentions.
说的跟自己没有参与其中似的?
Like you wasn't a part of it?
就算我在那
Even if I was there
也不意味我参与了这场杀戮
don't mean I participated in any killing.
该死 就像人们都说我在行刑队中
Hell, like people said I was in that firing squad
枪决了托尔伯特和...
that killed Tolbert and...
哦 行刑队?
Oh, firing squad?
大家都知道!
Everybody knows!
我是举起了枪
I raised my gun.
但我故意打偏了
I missed on purpose.
昨晚也一样
Last night was no different.
但你确实在那
You were there.
所以你是吉姆・万斯谋杀我全家的帮凶
So you helped Jim Vance murder my entire family?
不 该死的 我没有
Oh, hell no, I didn't.
这真让我恶心
You know, it made me sick.
见鬼 我要是知道他们会这么做
Hell, if I knew they was gonna do such,
我肯定不会去
I'd have never gone.
是那个弱智科顿朝爱丽菲尔开的枪
It was that weak-brained Cotton Top shot Alifair.
吉姆・万斯现在在庆祝了吧
That Jim Vance is celebrating now.
不 他没有
Oh, hell no, he ain't.
爸爸把他和盖打发到萨克尔山去避避风头
Pa sent him and Cap over Thacker mountain to lay low awhile.
他们在芒西湾附近猎鹿
They's a-hunting deer up big Muncey Creek,
就为了搞点吃的
tryin' to put food on the goddamn table,
我们家现在连商店都去不了
'cause our family can't even go to a store
因为可能会有麦考伊的赏金猎人伏击我们
without some McCoy bounty hunter ambushing us.
别这样
Come on.
咱们收拾一下行囊
You know what, let's pack the hell up.
收拾一下行囊
Let's pack the hell up.
咱们...
Let's...
咱们往西走 逃离...
let's go west, just get...
逃离所有这些悲伤和苦难
get away from all this grief and misery.
它让我们受尽折磨
It's tearing us apart.
跟我走吧 南茜
Go away with me, Nance.
咱们走 咱们走吧
Let's go. Let's go.
我要和一个真正的男人一起待在派克维尔
I'll be in Pikeville with a real man.
我和弗兰克・菲利普斯
Me and Frank Phillips,
要结婚了
we're getting married.
我是来自《纽约世界报》的T.C.克劳福德
T.C. Crawford from the New York world.
对这场血仇的起源我有几个问题
I have a few questions about the origin of this feud.
不是血仇
No feud,
至少我不这么认为
not from how I see it.
那你怎么形容它呢 先生?
Well, how would you describe it, sir?
一场多年来欺骗和谋杀
A many-year campaign of swindling and murdering
我家族的运动
against my family.
昂斯・哈特菲尔德和他的族人发起的?
By Anse Hatfield and his clan?
是恶魔昂斯・哈特菲尔德
Devil Anse Hatfield.
西弗吉尼亚州的威尔逊州长声称
Well, governor Wilson of West Virginia has said
杀害你儿子们的凶手
the men arrested for your sons' murders
是被非法逮捕的
were taken illegally.
那是文书工作上出现了错误
There was an error of paperwork.
我们的法庭会裁决的
Our courts will adjudicate it.
我的家被烧毁了 可不是文书错误
My house burnin' was no paper error.
法庭无法使我的女儿和我被枪杀的儿子复活
No court can resolve my daughter, my son shot dead,
我的妻子也受了重伤
my wife so grievously injured,
公正的上帝不会允许这些暴行!
atrocities that a just God would not allow!
我们能拍张照片吗 先生?
May we take a photograph, sir?
你的枪
Your weapon.
我想请你拿着它
I want you to hold it, please.
我们的读者会非常喜欢看这个的
Our readers will really appreciate this.
把枪稍微拿高一点
Just hold the gun up a little bit higher.
没事的 兰德尔
It's all right, Randall.
展示出我们对于公正的严肃态度
Shows we're serious about justice.
您看上去非常正直 先生
You look righteous, sir.
等会会闪一下
There's going to be a flash.
莎莉 你还觉得头疼吗?
Sally, you still getting them headaches?
还好吗?
You all right?
嗨 妈妈
Hey, mama.
是我 罗斯安娜
Hey, it's Roseanna.
- 罗西? - 是的
- Rosie? - Yeah.
需要什么吗?
Anything you need?
她...她很好
She... she's all right.
妈妈
Oh, mama.
我知道在哪能找着吉姆・万斯
I know where you can find Jim Vance.
是吗?
Yeah?
告诉我
Tell me about it.
嗯哼
Uhhuh.
别改变你的步速
Don't alter your pace.
别到处看
Don't look about.
有人躲在我们前面的树后面
There's men concealed in them trees up ahead of us.
是谁? 菲利普斯?
Who is it? Phillips?
大概是他
Most likely.
几年前就该杀掉那该死的狐狸
Should have killed that goddamn fox years ago.
听着 盖
Look here, Cap.
交火之后 你得活着
When all this starts, you not being dead,
你要逃下山去
you break downhill.
- 你听懂了吗 孩子? - 遵命
- You understand, son? - Yes, sir.
快逃
Skedaddle.
啊!
Ah!
趴下 吉姆!
Stay down, Jim!
快跑 盖!
Run, Cap!
逃啊!
Run!
没必要我们两人都在这里吃枪子
No sense in both of us eatin' these bastards' bullets!
啊!
Ah!
吉姆!
Jim!
该死的 孩子!
God damn it, boy!
我说 快逃!
I said, get!
不然我会从地狱回来揍你屁股
Or else I'll come back from hell and tan your hide!
吉姆!
Jim!
把那该死的步枪给我
Give me that damn rifle.
啊 该死的
Ah, shit.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
都别动!
Leave him be!
他是我的!
He's mine!
哦
Oh.
我非常非常抱歉
I'm terrible sorry,
小嚎尔斯
howls junior.
很抱歉
So sorry.
一切都要结束了
I do believe this is the end of the line.
我紧跟着就来 小家伙
I'll be right behind you, boy.
马上就来
Right behind you.
别开枪
Don't shoot.
还不能
Not yet.
是时候送你归西了
Time to meet your maker.
天堂还是地狱 吉姆叔叔?
Which way you gonna go, uncle Jim?
把我的靴子都弄脏了
Got my damn boots all dusty.
是盖!
It's Cap!
他受伤了!
He's hurt!
哈特菲尔德先生
Mr. Hatfield.
盖受了枪伤
Cap got shot.
天哪 发生什么了?
Lord Jesus, what happened?
放开他
Get away from him.
- 武装队抓住了吉姆叔叔 - 好了
- Posse got uncle Jim. - All right.
恶人弗兰克埋伏在树林中向他开了枪
Bad Frank shot him in an ambush.
杀了他的狗
Killed his dog.
有人向我开了一枪
Guy shot me,
完全没有预兆 妈妈
there ain't no lead in there, mama.
好了 好了
All right. All right.
我没事
I'm all right.
你说他们抓走了吉姆?
You said they got Jim?
他在哪里?
Where is he?
他在哪里 盖?
Where is he, Cap?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
他们...他死了 爸爸
They... he's dead, pa.
他们带走了他的尸体
They took his body.
好了 好了
All right. All right.
好了
All right.
- 抱歉 - 吉姆叔叔
- I'm sorry. - Uncle Jim.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
约翰斯在哪里?
Where's Johnse at?
他在他的小屋里吗?
He at his cabin?
恶人弗兰克下一个目标可能是他
Bad Frank is gonna probably hit him next.
我去找几个人赶去约翰斯那里
I'll get some boys to ride by Johnse,
确保他没事
make sure he's all right.
把他带到溪边去洗掉血和泥
Take him to the stream to wash off that blood and dirt.
我去拿点药和绷带
I'll get some tincture and bandages.
他们怎么会知道我们在那 爸爸?
How'd they know where we was, pa?
嗯?
Huh?
往常你的鼾声总是吵醒我
Your snoring used to keep me awake.
今天却很安静
Now it's the silence.
我脑子无法平静
My mind won't rest.
你在想吉姆叔叔?
You thinking about uncle Jim?
我总是在想有一天我不得不...
I always thought someday I'd have to...
不得不亲手杀了他
have to kill him myself.
但是...
Well...
盖没被杀真是个奇迹
It's a miracle Cap wasn't killed too.
只有两个人知道吉姆和盖去了哪里
Only two people knew where Jim and Cap had gone,
那天他们会在什么地方
where they'd be that day.
谁?
Who?
我...
Me...
和约翰斯
And Johnse.
你怎么知道?
How do you know that?
任何人都可能说漏嘴
Anybody could have said something.
我懂
I know.
不是 盖或者吉姆...
No, Cap or Jim...
我明白
I know.
我知道 因为我很确定
I know, 'cause I made sure.
约翰斯不是叛徒犹大
Johnse's no Judas.
不 他不是 但是有人因他而死 莉瓦西
No, he's not, but people died, Levicy.
但是 你不能说你没有一点责任?
Well, you can't say you didn't have a part in that?
我承认我也有责任
And that I'll have to live with,
但是我俩都知道我们的儿子不是一个谨慎的人
but we both know our boy's not a careful person,
尤其是跟女人在一起的时候
especially around women.
你打算怎么做?
What do you intend to do?
睡吧
Get some sleep.
安德森?
Anderson?
你也睡吧
You should too.
好孩子
Good boy.
嘿 爸爸
Hey, daddy.
你站在那里多久了?
How long you been standing there?
有一会了
A while.
前几天你在哪里?
Where were you the other day?
哦 我去布恩郡寄东西了
Oh, I was up in Boone county making a delivery,
你知道的
you know.
你 唔...
You, uh...
你今天早上要工作吗?
You going to work this morning?
我想我们可以一起去钓鱼
Thought you and me might go fishing.
今天?
Today?
等你干完手上的活 帮我的马装上鞍
When you finish there, saddle my horse.
好的
All right.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我和约翰斯需要谈谈
Me and Johnse are gonna have a talk.
我必须知道这是什么意思
I have to know what that means.
你觉得我会伤害他吗?
You think I mean him harm?
不然的话 让我听听是什么
I need to hear otherwise.
我需要听你亲口告诉我
I will hear you say it.
我带他去钓鱼 莉瓦西
I'm taking him fishing, Levicy.
好久不见 哥哥
So long, big brother.
你真的不想钓鱼?
You sure you don't want to fish?
我就来
I'm going to.
还记得上次
You remember the last time
你带我来这个同样的地方钓鱼吗?
you brought me out to this old fishing hole?
我想不起来了
I don't recall that.
我还记得
I do.
我知道 因为我当时坐在
I know, 'cause I was in that
那边的柳树的树枝上
willow tree over there up in that limb.
你记得你跟我说过什么吗?
You recall what you said to me?
我记得
I do.
你说 如果我掉进水里
You said if I fell in,
我会把鱼吓跑的
I was gonna scare the fish.
一旦我掉进去 可别太指望你
And once I was in, chances of you getting me out
会把我救出来 因为你不喜欢
weren't good on account that you were not partial
在冰水里洗澡
to cold water.
你记得你说过这话吗?
You recall having said that?
好吧 我还以为能把你逗笑呢 爸爸
Well, I believe I just coaxed a laugh out of you, pa.
该死 我都不记得上次看你笑是什么时候了
God damn, I don't remember the last time I seen that.
你跟那个麦考伊女孩的结局太糟糕了
It's too bad about you and the McCoy girl.
哪一个?
Which one?
那个跟了别的男人的女孩
The one that ran off with the man
而且还是杀你吉姆叔叔的男人
that killed your uncle Jim.
你记性很好 约翰斯
You recall pretty good, Johnse.
你想要跟我说什么吗?
Anything you want to say to me?
我知道我不该相信她 我很清楚这一点
I know I shouldn't have trusted her. I know that for damn sure.
我讨厌这一切
You know, I hate all this.
一直都是
I always have.
大概我只想要玩乐吧
I think all I ever wanted to do was play,
尽情地欢笑和玩乐
just laugh and play.
这里的人似乎都不会笑了
Yeah, it seems like nobody around here ever laughs anymore,
除非是哪个麦考伊家的人受伤或者死了
except maybe when a McCoy gets maimed or killed.
这对你来说是一个考验 爸爸
You know, that must be a trial for you, daddy,
我不像你一样
me not being like you.
你没有必要和我一样 约翰斯
You are who you are, Johnse.
不 我是说
No, what I mean is,
所有人都敬重你
everybody looks up to you,
甚至连你的哥哥都是
I mean, even your older brothers.
但是 却没有...
No, there ain't...
没有人敬重我
there ain't nobody looking up to me.
更可悲的是 有人说
Hell, there are those that say
淡毛科顿都比我有用
Cotton Top's of more use.
我都不知道该怎么待在这个家里
I don't know how to be in this family.
我记得...
I mean, I got...
记得所有的事情 你知道吗?
I got all the memories, you know?
我记得所有发生过的事
I know all that's happened.
只是...
I just...
我并不后悔成为哈特菲尔德家族的一员
I don't have the hate that comes with being a Hatfield.
当我抬头仰望的时候 爸爸
You know, I look up at that sky, pa,
看到白云悠闲地飘过
and those clouds going by.
我知道 它们正飞往
I'm telling you, I know they're headed
一个和这里截然不同的地方
somewhere different than what we got here.
我看过一些俄勒冈州的图片和故事
I seen these pictures and these stories about Oregon.
天哪 他们有大片的树木可以砍伐
Man, they got these millions of trees to be logged,
甚至比这里的更多
I mean, even more than here,
河里的有肥美的鱼
wild rivers with fish long as your arm,
不用跟麦考伊家的人打个你死我活
no McCoys to shoot at or get shot by.
那里简直是人间天堂
That's heaven on earth.
就是那样
That's what that is.
那里就是我向往的地方
That's where I aim to go.
在俄勒冈州你会停滞不前 约翰斯
You won't outrun yourself in Oregon, Johnse.
我可以问你个问题吗?
Can I ask you a question?
如果那天我掉下去了
If I would have fell in that day,
吓跑了那些鱼...
scared those fish...
你会任由我溺死吗?
Would you have let me drown?
是一只老熊啊
That's a big old bear.
它出现在我们背后 被约翰斯捕获了
Johnse bagged him when he come up behind us.
我都没看到它
I never seen him.
这孩子反应总是很快
That boy always did have quick reflexes.
他只是...
He's just...
拿那点俊俏的外表去玩了
Too damn handsome for his own good.
虽然 除了英俊的外表
Though, he's a lot like his daddy,
他很像他爸爸
except for the handsome part.
这孩子一点儿也不像我
Boy's nothing like me.
大冷天的早上你怎么来了?
What brings you out this frosty morn?
我们的诉求有了回音
Well, I got news about our appeal.
文迪州长正要把这些都
Governor Windy's taking it all the way
上报给美国最高法院
to the United States supreme court.
现在 我们也有法可依了 或许
Now we gonna be in the lawbooks, maybe.
救孩子们出狱
Get our boys out of jail,
回到家里去
back in their homes where they belong.
任何一个懂点法律知识的人
Anybody who knows anything about jurisprudence
都说这是毫无疑问的
says there ain't no doubt.
只有一个办法可以解决问题 哥哥
Only one thing gonna resolve this, big brother.
而它绝不会是什么法律女士
And it ain't miss jurisprudence.
不知道你们在这里计划什么 昂斯
I don't know what you're planning here, Anse,
但这场该死的战争
but all this damn bloodshed
是该结束了
and killing's got to stop.
希望吉姆叔叔是最后一个牺牲者
Uncle Jim was the last straw.
我要去自首
I'm turning myself in.
你疯了?
You insane?
那帮虚伪的家伙会让你脑袋开花的
Them blaggard's will shoot you down.
我已经放话给佩里・克莱因了
I already sent word to Perry Cline.
佩里・克莱因
Perry Cline.
你认为那个卑鄙小人会信守承诺?
You think that skunk will keep his word?
就这样定了 昂斯
It's done, Anse.
我要用最恰当的方式来结束这场战争
I'm gonna fight this thing the best way I know how.
在法庭上解决
I'm gonna fight it in the courtroom.
在肯塔基的法庭上
In a Kentucky courtroom.
但绝不是武力解决
But not with a damn gun.
我的枪从没让我失望过 沃尔
Well, guns never failed me, wall,
不像那些法官和律师
not like judges and lawyers.
那就只能采取我们之间
Well, it's gonna be the way it's always been
惯用的解决方式了 弟弟
between you and me, little brother.
你用你的办法解决 我用我的方式处理
You gonna handle things your way, and I'm gonna do them my way.
我从未告诉过你 我跟艾利生说过的一些话
Wall, I never told you about something I said to Ellison.
或许是他所记得的最后一件事 或许不是
May be the last thing he remembered, maybe not,
但却一直折磨着我
but it's haunted me ever since.
所以现在 我不想...
So right now, I don't want to...
现在 我不想对你说一些
Right now, I don't want to say something to you
我将来会后悔的话
I'm gonna regret.
你大可不必担心这些 昂斯
You ain't got no call to worry about that, Anse.
嗨
Hey.
我去会会法律女士 然后就来找你
I'll be seeing you right after I meet miss jurisprudence.
驾!
Ha! Come on.
过来
Get over here.
我是沃尔・哈特菲尔德法官
My name is justice wall Hatfield.
依照应有的法律程序
I've surrendered myself on a Kentucky warrant
我向肯塔基州法庭自首
for due process of the law.
哈特菲尔德 你被逮捕了
Hatfield, you're under arrest.
我是来自首的 菲利普斯
I'm turning myself in, Phillips.
休想靠我得到任何赏金
You'll collect no bounty on me.
分我一点儿吧 美女
Give me some of that, pretty lady.
人家不要了
I ain't gonna do that.
不 不要了
No, not now.
嗨 嗨 介意把老大借我一会吗 女士?
Hey, hey, you mind if I borrow my boss from you, ma'am?
《洛根旗帜》
Logan banner.
说哈特菲尔德准备再次战争了
Says Hatfield's getting ready for war again,
《洛根旗帜》
哈特菲尔德为战争做准备
在三个州的各个五金店
buying every hardware store in three states
大肆购买枪支弹药
out of guns and ammo.
不过是个乡巴佬
Hillbilly dirt rag.
不足为害
Means nothing.
喝点吧
You need a drink.
克莱因先生 什么事让你这么高兴?
Mr. Cline, what's your pleasure?
已经痛饮了一番
Already got a fine libation.
这不只是抓获沃尔・哈特菲尔德那么简单
I understand we're celebrating more
值得我们好好庆祝一场
than the capture of wall Hatfield.
见过弗兰克・菲利普斯夫人
Meet Miss Frank Phillips.
恭喜
Congratulations.
菲利普斯先生?
Mr. Phillips?
哈特菲尔德正在马特湾集合人马
A mob of Hatfields is forming over at mate creek,
恶魔昂斯亲自带领
Devil Anse himself at the lead.
好像朝这个方向过来了
Looks like they're a-fixing to ride this way.
哈特菲尔德是想把他的亲戚们从监狱里救出去
Hatfield's busting his relatives out of jail.
我们得阻止他 弗兰克
We got to stop him, Frank.
把警员们都集合起来
Round up the deputies.
列出每一个体格健壮的人
Enlist every able-bodied man you can.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
走 走
Come on. Come on.
是时候会会恶魔昂斯了
About time I see Devil Anse.
我们会赢的 克莱因先生 我们会的
We got this, Mr. Cline. We got this.
杀了他们
Kill them.
遵命 女士
Yes, ma'am.
一个都不要放过
Every single one.
好的 出发
All right, let's go.
快
Come on.
让法律见鬼去吧
The law be damned.
让哈特菲尔德见鬼去吧!
Hatfield be damned!
让上帝见鬼去吧!
God be damned!
你们通通见鬼去吧!
Damn you all to perdition!
1888年 葡萄湾之战
驾!
Hyah!
哈特菲尔德!
Hatfield!
麦考伊!
McCoy!
哈特菲尔德!
Hatfield!
开火!
Fire!
哈特菲尔德!
Hatfield!
去把老头拉回来
Get your old man back.
他这样会第一个死的
He's gonna be the first one killed.
好!
Yeah!
你就那么想死吗?
You trying to get yourself killed?
别管我!
Leave me be!
杀光他们!
Kill them all!
走开
Go.
快走开!
Shoo!
快!
Go!
你没事吧 爸爸?
You all right there, pop?
没事 继续
Yeah, go on.
该死的
Damn it.
该死!
God damn it!
这里! 他在这里!
Here! He's here!
滚回来打我啊!
Come back and fight!
啊!
Ah!
比利
Billy.
找个掩护趴好
Find cover, and stay put.
是个陷阱!
It's a trap!
是个...
It's a...
喂 回来!
Hey, get back!
大家回马那里去!
Get everybody back to the horses!
昂斯
Anse.
我们得赶快撤 昂斯
We got to get out of here, Anse.
他们发起了夹攻
They're flanking us on both sides.
妈妈
Mama.
孩子
Ah, son.
盖!
Cap!
- 盖! - 干嘛?
- Cap! - What?
传我的话
Pass the word.
我们准备撤退
We're pulling out.
撤退!
Move!
乔!
Joe!
过来帮我抬一下比利
Help me here with Billy.
我要把他带回他妈妈身边
I'm taking him home to his mama.
他们撤退了
They're quitting the field.
我们走
Let's go.
回来!
Back!
招呼他
Oh, call out to him.
等他一站起来我就爆他的头
When he stands up, I'll blow his head off.
住手!
Hold off!
我们抓到一个俘虏
We got us a prisoner.
他们没有
They don't.
我投降!
I give up!
就是说我们赢了
Means we won the day.
把他抓过来!
Go get him!
我们赢了
We won.
我赢了
I won.
保佑圣婴耶稣
Bless the baby Jesus.
没事吧? 来
You all right? Come on.
走!
Move!
站起来
Stand up.
走 起来!
Come on, get!
血仇
还有几步
Just a few steps more.
医生说走走路有益于你的康复
Doctor said it was good for you to walk.
不是这间房子
The room is not right.
我知道 妈妈
I know, mama.
这是佩里・克莱因的房子
It's Perry Cline's house.
所以看上去不一样
That's why it looks different.
坐
Here.
我不喜欢佩里・克莱因
I don't like Perry Cline.
我知道 妈妈
I know, mama.
我死后
After I die,
我希望能用电销毁我的尸体
I would like my body destroyed by electricity.
你还记得吗 罗斯安娜?
Can you remember that, Roseanna?
记得 妈妈
Yes, mama.
我不喜欢佩里・克莱因
I don't like Perry Cline.
我知道 妈妈
I know, mama.
兰德尔叔叔?
Uncle Randall?
兰德尔叔叔 我们到了
Uncle Randall, we're here.
他妈的我们来这里干嘛?
The hell are you doing here?
弗兰克・菲利普斯让我带你到克莱因先生家
Frank Phillips asked me to take you to Mr. Cline's house.
你让我恶心
You disgust me.
你妈妈怎么样了 罗斯安娜?
How's your mother, Roseanna?
她...
She's, uh...
她好些了
She's better in some ways.
还没痊愈
She's not right yet.
我听说你也病了
I hear tell you're sick as well.
我们曾经是朋友 南茜
We was friends, Nancy.
你为什么要这样伤害我?
Why'd you hurt me the way you did?
和约翰斯交往你是自作自受
You hurt yourself taking up with Johnse.
我跟他结婚则是把你从痛苦的深渊里拯救出来
Me marrying him just saved you a whole lot of pain.
你爱他吗?
You love him?
从未爱过
I never did.
我恨他
I hate him,
就跟恨所有该死的哈特菲尔德家的人一样
just like all the demon Hatfields.
我跟约翰斯在一起绝不是想伤害你
Me and Johnse was never nothing against you.
只想跟他们算清旧账
It's just plain old revenge.
从小我就发誓要消灭哈特菲尔德家族
I swore to killing Hatfields when I was young.
我心中只有复仇
Revenge is all I got inside of me.
驾
Yah.
好消息 法官
Good news, judge.
最高法院做出了判决 相信这判决是乱来的
The supreme court has ruled, incorrectly, I believe,
不经过西弗吉尼亚州的同意就把你们抓来
that taking you people without West Virginia's consent
是违法的
was illegal.
我们没事了?
So we going free?
你们听见了吗?
Well, you hear that?
我们自由了!
We're going free!
塞尔柯克
Selkirk.
律师能笑得出来说明事情没那么简单
A lawyer's smile promises more to come.
法院还判决了...这个较合理...
Court also ruled... properly this time...
基于你们已经在肯塔基州
that since you're already in Kentucky,
只要你们再次被合法逮捕
as long as you're legally rearrested,
就可以接受审判
you can be brought to trial.
菲利普斯先生?
Mr. Phillips?
先生们 你们被逮捕了
Gentlemen, y'all are under arrest.
是你的女儿罗斯安娜
It's your daughter Roseanna.
我出现在你的身后
I'm coming up behind you.
站在你身旁
I'm standing next to you.
你看见我了吗 爸爸?
You see me, poppy?
你听见我说话了吗?
You hear my voice?
听见了
I hear you.
死去的孩子们
Dead children,
死去的外孙女
a dead grandchild,
疯了的妻子
a mad wife.
每个人都认为你会与尚在人世的女儿紧紧相拥
Anybody'd think you'd embrace a still-living daughter.
我小时候
When I was a little girl,
你曾经跟我说 我是你的最爱的女儿
you once told me I was your favorite.
几年来我一直靠此生活着
I lived on that for years.
就是这个小小的肯定能让我坚信
Just that tiny bit of approval made me believe
在这世界上我无所不能
I could do anything in this world.
因为你会给予我告诫
'Cause for all your preaching
你会为我祈祷...
and all your praying...
在我们家 你就是上帝
In our house, you were God.
让我来
Here. Let me take that for you.
你今天看上特别苍白
You're looking particularly pale today.
你没事吧?
Are you well?
没事
Yeah.
谢谢关心
Thanks for asking.
罗斯安娜
Roseanna.
你知道 我...
You know my...
我几年前的那个提议...
my offer of years ago...
现在还有效
It still stands.
哦 佩里
Oh, Perry.
你不会要我的
You don't want me.
我已经是个废人了
I'm all used up.
别这么说
Don't say that.
我真的想跟你在一起
I do want you.
我只是想让你重拾欢乐...
I just want to make you happy...
是啊
Yeah.
还要照顾你
And take care of you.
我得把这些杯子给洗了
I should probably just do these dishes up.
我一直爱着你
I've always loved you.
罗斯安娜
Roseanna.
罗斯安娜!
Roseanna!
兰德尔!
Randall!
医生!
Doc!
罗斯安娜 她不...她不动弹了!
Roseanna, she's not... she's not moving!
她晕倒了!
She just fell!
我不知道怎么回事!
I don't understand!
兰德尔 快进来! 哦 上帝!
Randall, get in here! Oh, my God!
罗斯安娜 你听见我说话了吗?
Roseanna, can you hear me?
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
她在流血! 她流血了!
She's bleeding! She's bleeding!
她怎么了?
What's wrong with her?
孩子他妈
There, there, mother.
罗斯安娜・麦考伊之墓 生卒年 1859年至1888年
一切都会好起来的
It'll be fine, just fine.
拉瑟福德医生说 在列克星敦有一家医院
Doc rutherford says there's a hospital in Lexington
可以医好你的病
that can help you.
你必须让自己心碎
You must let your heart break.
只有当你内心最脆弱的部分受到重创之时
Only when the most innocent part of you suffers
你才可以有所作为
can there be change.
否则你将一事无成
Else nothing remains of you.
她今天可以开口说话了吗 兰德尔?
Is she able to talk today, Randall?
是的 但是她说的话没有逻辑性
She speaks, but her words carry no meaning.
至少比她苦苦哀号和喋喋不休好得多
An improvement on all her wailing and rabbit noises.
你把我送走不是为了让我康复
You're not sending me away to get better.
你把我送走
You're sending me away
然后你就可以和佩里・克莱因为所欲为
so you can go to hell with Perry Cline.
驾
Yah.
这是真的吗 我谋杀她在先?
Is it true that I murdered her in the first degree?
爱丽菲尔・麦考伊
Alifair McCoy,
你谋杀了她
you murdered her.
有人指使你这样回答吗?
Did anyone tell you to say this?
你要说没有人指使你
You said to say that no one did.
你的意思是说 没有人指使你说任何话?
You mean no one told you to say anything?
只要说我谋杀她在先
Only that I murdered her in the first degree.
我请求法庭
I beg the court.
我的当事人是一个可怜单纯的傻瓜
My client's nothing but a poor, simpleminded fool.
天生如此
Born that way.
既然他已经认罪
Now, he admits his guilt
请求法庭从宽发落
and throws himself on the mercy of the court.
沃尔・哈特菲尔德
Wall Hatfield,
终身监禁
life in prison.
塞尔柯克・麦考伊
Selkirk McCoy,
终身监禁
life in prison.
亚历克斯・梅塞尔
Alex Messer,
终身监禁
life in prison.
"淡毛科顿" 艾利生・芒茨
"Cotton Top" Ellison Mounts,
处以绞刑
death by hanging.
没关系
That's fine.
因为恶魔昂斯 盖 还有其他所有人
'Cause Devil Anse, Cap, and all of them
将会在午夜时分 全副武装前来
gonna come at midnight all armed and terrible,
骑着黑色的战马 马蹄闪闪发光
riding dark horses with lightning hooves
他们是不死的战神
that don't never die.
他们不会让我被绞死的
They won't let me hang.
放他出去
I'm letting him out.
给我钥匙
Give me the keys.
放他出去
I'm letting him out.
他们唯一要处死的那个哈特菲尔德的人
The only Hatfield they're hanging
他是无辜的
is the one that don't deserve it.
处死一个...
It's bad luck to hang a...
处死一个智障的孩子 这是不道德的
it's bad luck to hang a half-wit.
那只是妇人之见 兰德尔
No, that's an old wives' tale, Randall.
公正何在?
Where is my justice?
何在?
Where is it?
你应该回家 清醒清醒
You know, you need to go home and sober up some.
你
You
你们可以苟活于世...
you get to live...
而我的孩子们却要在坟墓里慢慢腐烂
While my sons, my daughter rot in their graves.
我也该把你放出去
I might as well let you out too.
给我该死的钥匙
Give me the goddamn keys.
把他弄出去
Get him out of here.
不知何时我们当中的一人
Was there a point where one of us
才能放下这些无谓的执念?
could have gave way to stop all this nonsense?
我想你可以考虑一下
I guess you can contemplate that.
是你没有放下
You still got something left.
你到底想要什么 兰德尔?
What do you want, Randall?
嗯?
Hmm?
你想从这人生中获得些什么?
What do you want out of this life?
但求平静度过
Just get through it.
如果说有两个人一直彼此误会的话
If ever two men misunderstood each other,
那无疑说的就是我们
it was us.
这一切何时才能结束?
So when does it end?
当流尽最后一滴血之时
When there's no blood left to be spilled.
没有用的 兰德尔
That way don't work, Randall.
我们已经试过了
We tried that way.
我计划着在夜深人静的时候
I figure we go in the dead of night
当浓雾弥漫之时
when the fog is thickest.
我们派五个人前往北部连续扫射
Get five men blazing away in the north end
在派克维尔制造一起前所未有的骚乱
causing commotion like Pikeville had never seen.
然后我们冲进监狱把其他人...
And we charge that jail with everybody else...
谁都不准闯监狱救人
Nobody's busting anybody out of jail.
什么?
What?
沃尔叔叔 你的哥哥
Uncle wall, your big brother,
无辜受罪
got life for doing nothing.
沃尔不会跟你们走的
Wall wouldn't go anyways.
他希望通过上诉可以获释
He's fighting it with appeals.
他希望光明正大地走出监狱
Still thinks he'll get out legal.
那淡毛科顿呢?
What about Cotton Top?
我们可是告诉各大报刊
We're telling every goddamn newspaper in the country
我们会营救他的
we're coming for him.
淡毛科顿被处死之时
When Cotton Top's hanged,
便是麦考伊家族放下屠刀之日
it'll take away the McCoy bloodlust.
什么时候行刑?
When he's hanged?
那么科顿是我们的犹大羊吗?
So cotton's our Judas goat?
犹大羊 把羊群引领至屠宰场的领路羊
必须有人委曲牺牲才能结束这一切
Somebody's got to bend to stop it.
兰德尔不肯 那么...
Randall can't, so...
只能由我来做
It's got to be me.
爸爸 你...你做得够多了
Pa, you... you done enough.
是时候我来接手了
It's time I take over.
我不希望你变成我这样子
I don't want that for you.
你肯不肯听我一句劝告?
Weren't you listening to me?
盖 你...你终有一天会有自己的孩子
Cap, you gonna... you gonna have children one day,
你的孩子们
and your children,
他们将不再关心
they're not gonna care about our old grudges
祖先们的恩恩怨怨
and slights from long ago.
而他们的孩子...
And their children...
他们的孩子们甚至不会知晓这些
Hell, their children won't even know about it.
孩子 是时候放下过去继续前进了
It's time for us to move on, son.
哦
Oh.
该死的
Damn.
Damn it.
莉瓦西 你还好吗?
Levicy, you all right?
我想念约翰斯
I miss Johnse.
我想念我们的孩子
I miss our son.
有时我在想
I sometimes wonder
如果我当时同意他和第一个女孩的婚事
how different things might have turned out
事情是否会有所不同
had I allowed him to marry the first one.
罗斯安娜也是麦考伊家族的人
Well, Roseanna was a McCoy.
我们不得不做出我们认为正确的判断
We had to do what we thought was right.
让我看看 让我看看
Let me see. Let me see.
噢!
Ow!
离开这里!
Let's get out of here!
这一切快点结束吧
Got to get this thing over with
要不然又得开战了
before we go to war again.
再说一次 到底什么事情如此重要
Tell me again, what's so important
我们为何要盛装打扮女孩们
we had to dress up the girls
然后一路把她们带到这里
and bring them all the way here
来看一个几乎看不清的东西?
for something you can hardly see?
这是见证历史的时刻
This is history.
哈特菲尔德和麦考伊久负盛名
Hatfields and McCoys are famous.
因为什么?
Famous for what?
互相残杀
Killing each other.
过来
Come here.
大家在这里集合一下
Let's gather over here.
你们当中大多数人都设过陷阱
Most of you have done some trapping
有时候会偶尔见到一条雪狐
and, on occasion, found a winter fox
扯断腿 从陷阱中逃脱出去
that's left his leg behind him in the trap.
如今我们正面临这样的困境
So it is with us on this difficult day.
不得不做出这样的牺牲
Leave our leg behind,
否则就坐等灭亡
or die in the trap.
这里有一封即将寄给报社的信件
Got a letter here that we're gonna send to the newspapers.
我希望你们能够首先听一下
I wanted you to all hear it first.
"我不..."
"I do not..."
"我不希望这段世仇再延续下去"
"I do not wish to keep the old feud alive."
"我想所有人 包括我自己"
"I suppose everybody, like myself,
"厌倦了所谓的哈特菲尔德和麦考伊的家族恩怨"
"is tired of the names 'Hatfield' and 'McCoy'
"以及和平年代的边界战争"
"and border warfare in a time of peace."
"我厌倦了战争"
"The war spirit in me has abated."
"我虔诚地为眼前和平美景而欣喜"
"And I sincerely rejoice at the prospect of peace."
"我把一生都献给无休止的战争"
"I've devoted my life to arms,
"而我们在这场可憎的争斗中"
"and we have undergone a fearful loss"
"失去了我们平静的生活"
"of Noble lives and valuable property"
"以及我们宝贵的财富"
"in this hateful struggle."
哈特菲尔德的人让我这样做的
The Hatfields made me do it.
他们用所谓的爱哄骗了我
They hornswoggled me with love.
"我们如同亚当"
"We, being like Adam,
"并非始作俑者"
"are not the first transgressors.
"我请求放下心中恩怨 和平相处"
"And I propose to rest in the spirit of peace."
- 谢谢 女士 - 不用客气
- Thank you, ma'am. - Obliged.
警长大人 我的名字是亚历山大
Sheriff, my name is Alexander.
我是您忠实的崇拜者
I'm a big fan of yours.
亚历山大?
Alexander?
谢谢 孩子
Well, thank you, son.
恶人弗兰克就在这里 就在这里
"Bad Frank" there, right there.
恭喜你 弗兰克
Congratulations, Frank.
我看过了
I read it.
这...
It's...
其实 你也应该恭喜我一下
Well, I, too, am to be congratulated.
这位是卡罗琳・罗斯女士
Meet Miss Carolyne Roes,
来自列克星敦的罗斯家族
of the Roes of Lexington.
她是我的未婚妻
She's my fiancee.
他们拥有半个郡的家业
They own half the county
还拥有数量可观的优良赛马
and quite a stable of fine racehorses.
你喜欢她们的年轻 是不是 克莱因?
You like them young, don't you, Cline?
简直是老牛吃嫩草
You cradle-robbing snake.
她又不是醉了
She ain't no drunkard,
这个谎话连篇的可笑东西
and this laughable pack of lies ain't nothing
不过是浪费了一张纸罢了
but a waste of cheap paper.
狗娘养的!
You son of a bitch!
来啊!
Come on!
随时奉陪!
Any time!
老大 住手!
Boss, come on!
滚出去!
Get out of here!
老大? 老大?
Boss? Boss?
我会悼念他的
I shall miss him.
只有恶人弗兰克才能杀了哈特菲尔德家的人!
Bad Frank could kill Hatfields like no one else!
1914年 肯塔基州
我来找你了
I'm coming after you,
恶魔昂斯!
Devil Anse!
你听到我说话了吗?
You hear me?
我来地狱见你了!
I'm coming to hell after you!
? 我们相聚河畔 ?
Gather at the river
? 有光明天使 ?
Where bright angel feet
? 立其间 ?
Have trod
我现在施洗于你 使你归入圣父 圣子
I baptize you in the name of the father, the son,
和圣灵的名下
and the holy spirit.
阿门
Amen.
? 我们相聚河畔 ?
Gather at the river
? 佳美的 ?
The beautiful
? 那佳美的河畔 ?
The beautiful river
? 与众圣徒相聚 ?
Gather we the saints
? 在河畔 ?
At the river
? 此河流自 ?
That flows by the throne
? 宝座前 ?
Of God
哈特菲尔德和麦考伊的这两个名字
无意中在美国变得家喻户晓
他们之间史诗般的血仇 长期的争斗
使他们两个家族渐行渐远 但也使他们永远联系在一起
一个名字的提起 总会伴随着另一个名字
在138年后的2003年 两个家族六十个后裔
共同签署了一份象征和平的条约
哈特菲尔德和麦考伊 最终停战...
莎莉・麦考伊
兰德尔・麦考伊
据说莎莉・麦考伊死于一家精神病院...
兰德尔・麦考伊长眠于他爱妻身旁
沃尔・哈特菲尔德
沃尔・哈特菲尔德再也没能上诉...
他在获刑几个月后便死于监狱
约翰斯・哈特菲尔德
在约翰斯・哈特菲尔德从俄勒冈州返回后 被判终身监禁
由于在一场持刀攻击中救了监狱长 约翰斯获得提前释放...
之后他又经历了四次婚姻
盖・哈特菲尔德
盖・哈特菲尔德成为了一名律师...
后来又成为了一名副警长
伊莱亚斯・"好人利亚斯"・哈特菲尔德
伊莱亚斯・哈特菲尔德离开马特湾组建了一个家庭...
他的儿子亨利・D・哈特菲尔德 成为了西弗吉尼亚州州长和美国参议员
佩里・克莱因
佩里・克莱因在审判两年后去世
南茜・麦考伊
弗兰克・菲利普斯
南茜・麦考伊-哈特菲尔德-菲利普斯 在恶人弗兰克・菲利普斯死后两年去世...
她葬于他身旁
恶魔昂斯・哈特菲尔德
昂斯在睡梦中平静地死去... 超过五千人参加了他的哀悼会
莉瓦西在八年后去世
一座恶魔昂斯的雕像立于意大利 表达他们无尽的哀思